Dmitrii Maksimov

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER · DATA SCIENTIST

Erlangen, Germany

📱 +49 15203762106 | 🗷 maksimov.dmitry.m@gmail.com | 2000 Hall January 28th, 1998 | 200 Maksimov-Dmitry | 200 Maksimov-

Summary_

Data/Software Engineer at fintech company T.C.R. International and Working Student Data Scientist at GFK. Worked as a Data Scientist at the ratailing company SDVOR in Moscow. 3+ years of diverse data science experience with specialties in market research, data visualization, market optimization and model deployment. 2+ year of diverse data/software engineering experience with specialties in pipelines integration using Airflow, architecure design using AWS, database maintenance and deployment using docker

In addition, while studying at the university and various courses(e.g. MADE from VK), I learned many skills like: **NLP, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Pytorch, Spark, Hadoop, Scala, Recommender Systems, kubernetes, mlflow, algorithms and data structures**.

Love to share knowledge with different communities. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for various tasks and learning new technologies and tools.

Skills_

MLOps AWS, Docker, GitHub, Retool, Linux, Bash, REST API

Machine Learning, Statistical Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Probability Theory, ETL, Vertica, Search Engine Optimization,

PostgreSQL, Market Research, Parsing, Pandas, Streamlit

Programming Python, SQL, SAS base, LaTeX **Languages** Russian, English, German

Work Experience

GFK Nuremberg, Germany

Data Scientist & Work Study

Apr. 2022 - Present

- · Creating a tool to compare segmentations and their impact on the market
- Creating a method to detect AoI(areas of interests)
- Investigating cannibalisation effects
- Evaluating competitors algorithm
- Stack: Python, Google Cloud Platform, Streamlit, PostgreSQL

T.C.R. International Cyprus

Data/Software Engineer Sep. 2021 - Present

- Creating and maintaining processes for financial systems(e.g. locates, charging, symbols databased maintaining)
- Stack: Python, AWS, Airflow, PostgreSQL, Retool, REST API, Docker

SDVOR Moscow, Russia

• Creating an attribution model in advertising for SDVOR site using Markov chain

- Programming ETL workflows for competitors site's parsing
- · Creating service to optimize price for sales using SAS, python, SQL
- Creating computer vision model to compare planorgam and realogram via photo in a shop
- Creating telegram-bot as a server for different tasks
- Stack: Python, SAS, Vertica, PostgreSQL, Telegram API

Education

DATA SCIENTIST

BMSTU(Bauman Moscow State Technical University)

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

• GPA - 4.42, max - 5.0

BMSTU(Bauman Moscow State Technical University)

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

• Finished 1 semester

FAU(Friedrich-Alexander-Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg)

M.S. IN DATA SCIENCE

Moscow, Russia

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2020

Apr. 2020 - Jan. 2022

Moscow, Russia

Sep. 2020 - Jun. 2021

Erlangen-Nürnberg, Germany

Oct. 2021 - Present

Extracurricular Activity

MADE at VK

Moscow, Russia

STUDENT

Sep. 2022 - PRESENT

- Gained expertise in different areas of ML (e.g. NLP, DL, CV, MLOps, basic ML, Python, ML in BigData, etc)
- Core member in a project to create a recommendation system for articles' authors

ML at Mail.ru Group

Moscow, Russia

STUDENT

Sep. 2020 - Jan. 2021

• Gained knowledge in basic ML

Certificates

Oct. 2022 Completion of the Deep Learning Exercise, FAU

Mar. 2020 Labeled data learning, Coursera

Mar. 2020 Math and Python for data analysis, Coursera

2019 **C/C++**, Mail.ru Group

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL AWARDS

Jan. 2023 8th Place, Tensor Tournament

Erlangen, Germany

DOMESTIC AWARDS

2021 **1st Place**, SDVOR Hacking Competition

Tyumen, Russia